John N. Rowe III papers, Inclusive: 1510-1989, undated, Bulk: 1830-1880
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
John N. Rowe III papers
Inclusive: 1510-1989, undated, Bulk: 1830-1880
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
2750
Rowe, III, John N.
44 document boxes and 5 oversized boxes
The John N. Rowe III papers consist of original manuscripts, legal documents, financial bonds, currency, and printed items relating to the early history of Texas and Mexico, as well as some early United States documents. Included are rare autographs of Stephen F. Austin, Sam Houston, and James W. Fannin.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Poor.
Biography/Profile
John N. Rowe III was born to John Nelson and Margaret Elizabeth Rowe around 1937 in Dallas, Texas. From a young age, he began collecting bank notes, and this hobby soon turned into a passion. He began donating his collection of papers to The Texas Collection in 1985, with the last donation in 1991.
Today, Rowe is one of the foremost numismatic dealers in the United States, earning the Lifetime Achievement Award from the Professional Numismatic Guild in 2009.
Scope and Content
The John N. Rowe III papers span from 1510 to 1989, with the bulk of the material covering 1830-1880. The papers predominately deal with Galveston county, though Nacogdoches, Texas and New Orleans, Louisiana are also featured prominently. The majority of the papers were originally identified individually and that detail of processing is maintained throughout. The materials are now divided into three series: I. Spanish Documents, II. Early Texas Documents, and III. Early United States Documents.
The first series, Spanish Documents, contains Spanish language materials from Spain and Mexico. There are religious proclamations, political declarations, general correspondence, and financial records in this series. It also contains a concentration of documents about Puerto Rico and a group of around 150 documents to and from a Señor Antonio de Perez Galvez.
The Early Texas Documents series contains materials that are pre-Republic of Texas up to the early 20th Century. You can find many of Austin's Old 300 in this section of the papers. It is further divided into four subseries: correspondence, legal, financial, and other. The correspondence subseries consists of general correspondence of different individuals, among them Sam Houston, Stephen F. Austin and Moses Austin. The largest section, legal, consists of materials covering land grants, land titles, wills, marriages, court documents, and documents pertaining to legal representation. Notably in this subseries are two muster rolls from the Army of The Republic of Texas in 1840. The muster rolls are of Company E, 1st Texas Infantry Regiment, under Colonel Edward Burleson. The third subseries, financial, is made up of financial documents in the form of treasury warrants, inventories, receipts, bonds, Republic of Texas and Civil War currency, and checks. Other, the fourth subseries, contains materials in other languages than English and Spanish, early flyers, sheet music, invitations, tickets, circulars, publications, a section of letters and documents from the Stiles family, and a James W. Fannin letter from Cuba in 1832.
The third series, Early United States Documents, contains early materials from states other than Texas, correspondence, publications, treaties, Civil War currency, and United States currency.
The strength of the papers lies in the collective vision and nature of the documents themselves, first as historic pieces and then as a whole, and what they say about early Texas and Mexico. Each item is unique and valuable but, taken together, gives a broad glimpse into the legal, political and financial matters that helped to shape the state of Texas.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, the John N. Rowe III papers were somewhat organized by number and name, and foldered down to the item level. After discussion, it was decided to go ahead and process the papers down to the item level. Along with processing at the item level, folders would be named according to names of individuals mentioned on documents within the folder when possible. A native Spanish speaker helped identify the names in the Spanish language documents, along with a Spanish professor who also served as a consultant.
Partial inventory lists were available for reference prior to this finding aid. Currently, the collection is organized in three series: I. Spanish Documents, II. Early Texas Documents, and III. Early United States Documents.
The Spanish documents contain a section of letters to and from a Señor Conde Perez Galvez and were numbered 1-151, and a section of letters dealing with Puerto Rico were numbered 152-237. That numbering system has been maintained physically, but the folders have been identified with names for ease of identification. Following the Puerto Rican section is a section that contains proclamations, decrees, municipal and state documents. The remainder of the Spanish series contains general correspondence that is arranged in alphabetical order.
The English Documents series is arranged alphabetically by last name within the different subseries, as is the United States Documents series.
Because these papers were collected individually for the most part, there is general inconsistency in the use of the word "and" as well as the ampersand (&) within the documents. This fact is reflected in the folder titles and headings, and these inconsistencies were kept in processing. Likewise, unusual or irregular spellings were also kept.
The condition of the documents range from extremely fragile to good. Most documents are sleeved and cannot be removed from their enclosures. Please use caution when handling these documents, especially any that are found unenclosed.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 2750. Acquired 1984-09-27
Related Resources
Related finding aids
Related references
Coinweek, 2011 August 15.
Rowe-Barr Collection of Texas Currency, Southern Methodist University. Accessed on 2018 July 20.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Austin, Stephen F. (Stephen Fuller), 1793-1836.; Houston, Sam, 1793-1863.
Places
Galveston (Tex.) -- History.; Mexico -- History.; Nacogdoches County (Tex.); New Orleans (La.) -- History.; Texas -- History -- 19th century.; Texas -- History -- 20th century.; Texas -- History.
Subjects
Land grants -- Texas.; Land titles -- United States.; Paper money -- Confederate States of America.; Paper money -- Texas.; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- Texas.
Genres
Business correspondence.; Correspondence.; Law materials.; Manuscripts.; Money. gmgpc; Personal correspondence.; Records (Documents)
- Spanish Documents, 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Poor.
  Biography/Profile
  The Spanish Documents series contains correspondence, official municipal documents, preprinted government documents, incomplete documents, a ledger, receipts and a typewritten transcript. Notable among these items is a 151 piece section of correspondence to and from Conde Antonio de Perez Galvez from 1808, and a section of 86 documents relating to Puerto Rico from the 1850s. There are also State documents relating to San Luis Potosi and other Mexican States, and a 1831 hymn book from Santa Teresa de Jesus, Mexico. Due to the age and fragile nature of these documents, they are placed in protective sleeves and cannot be removed. Please use caution in handling them.
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Cavallero del Orden de Santiago, Francisco Alvarez, 1808 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Navarro, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Joseph Castilla, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Francisco Rendon, 1808 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Francisco Diaz de Ravago, circa 1806-1808 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - De Galvez, Antonio Perez, Felipe de Lara, 1808 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - de Otano, D. Pedro Ruiz, Perez GalveZ, 1808 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Vivanco y Como, 1808 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Joseph Antonio, 1808 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Pedro Otero, 1808 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Martin de la Rival, 1808 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Francisco Gamino, 1808 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Navarro, 1808 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose ? Aysa, 1808 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Vincente Barros de Alemparte, 1808 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Manuel Dias de los Rios, 1808 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Francisco Triarte, 1808 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Antonio Savarrieta, 1808 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Jose Maria Lopez Cascos, 1808 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Vivanco y Como, 1808 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, T. Murphy, 1808 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, 1808 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Pedro Camacho y Texeda, 1808 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, T. Murphy, 1808 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Antonio Torres, 1808 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Antonio Ypina, 1808 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Antonio Savarrieta, 1808 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Juan Gutierrez Zamora, 1808 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Orteoa, 1808 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Otano, Pedro Ruiz, Senor Conde de Perez Galvez, 1808 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - de Galvez, Antonio Perez, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Perez Galvez, Senor Antonio, Esteban Melgar, 1808 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Francisco de Chavarria, 1808 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Navarro, 1808 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Otano, Pedro Ruiz, Perez Galvez, 1808 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, 1808 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, 1808 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Antonio, Matias Madrid, 1808 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jorantes, 1808 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Antonio, Eula Reforma, 1808 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Pedro, Perez Galvez, 1808 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Perez Galvez, Senor Antonio, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Francisco Alcozes, 1808 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Antonio Juan [illegible], 1808 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Fernando de Cordova, 1808 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Rafael de Orteoa, circa 1808 Jun e1 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Maria Josefa Fernandez de Condesa, 1808 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Joseph Antonio, 1808 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Simon de Viegas, 1808 June 5 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - de Galvez, Antonio Perez, Garcia Rebolla, 1808 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Antonio, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Unidentified, 1808 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - de Galvez, Antonio Perez, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Antonio, Martin Del Golido, 1808 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - de Galvez, Senor Coronel Antonio, Canat, 1808 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Joseph Antonio, 1808 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Manuel Merino, 1808 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Francisco Fernandez de la [illegible], 1808 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Manuel [illegible]? Garcia [illegible], 1808 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Unidentified, Joseph Antonio, 1808 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Coronel, unidentified, circa 1808 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Joseph Antonio, 1808 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, [illegible] de Leon y collantes, 1808 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Pedro de Antoneli, 1808 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Joseph Antonio, 1808 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Dr. Ivan Jose Roman, Juan Sojoes Pontillo, Jose Antonio Francoso, Jacobo M. Santos, Juan Dominguez, Manuel Francisco de Arbide, Valentin Gomez de Drada, 1808 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Perez Galvez, Senor Antonio, Otreoa, circa 1808 July 1 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Jose Cobo Sabin, 1808 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Govantes y Sederma, 1808 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan [illegible] de Flores, 1808 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Alcala de Olmo, 1808 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Maria de Aysa, 1808 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Perez Galvez, Senor Antonio, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Pedro de Antoneli, 1808 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Ignacio de Legaspi, 1808 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Martin de Gollado, 1808 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Rafael Angel Traldon y Mendoza, 1808 July 23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Joseph Antonio, 1808 July 23 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Martin de la Riva, 1808 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - de Perez, Antonio, Maria Madrid, 1808 July 29 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Antonio, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Govantes y Sederma, 1808 July 31 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Coronel Conde, Antonio de Velasco y Perez, 1808 July (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Dabila, 1808 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Ortega, 1808 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Joaquin Pelaes, 1808 September 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Perez Tejada, 1808 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - de Perez Galvez, Sneor Conde, Narciso Maria Loreto de la Canal, 1808 September 4 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Joseph Zambrano, 1808 September 5 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 September 6 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - (de Perez Galvez), Sr. Colonel, Jose Maria Lopez, 1808 September 10 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - de Perez Galvez, Jose Antonio, Jose Antonio C. Ballin, 1808 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Govantes y Sederma, 1808 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Manuel Lanuza, 1808 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Vicente T. Miranda, 1808 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Eugenio Juarregui Sologurem, 1808 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Dabila, 1808 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, J.N. Oviedo, 1808 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Govantes Y Sederma, 1808 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Narciso Maria Loreto de la Canal, 1808 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Pedro de Antoneli, 1808 September (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Govantes y Sederma, 1808 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose de Aysa, 1808 October 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, R. Corral, 1808 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Govantes y Sederma, 1808 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Cobo Labin, 1808 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - de Perez Galvez, J.N. Oviedo, 1808 August 4 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Gerardo Garcia, 1808 August 6 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor conde, unidentified, 1808 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Francisco Triarte, 1808 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Martin del Gollado, 1808 August 12 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor conde, Jose Castilla, 1808 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Jose Francisco Gamino, 1808 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Canal, 1808 August 14 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, M. Fuentes, 1808 August 17 (Folder 42)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Leonardo Sanchez del Villar, 1808 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Manuel Y. Garcia, 1808 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Josefa del Rey, 1808 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - de Perez Galvez, Denor Conde, Martin del Gollado, 1808 August 25 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan, 1808 August 26 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Manuel de la Huerta, 1808 August 29 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 August 30 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Pedro de Alonso, 1808 August 31 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Lost Tratantes de S. Miguel, 1808 August 29 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, El Conde de Medurra y Forros, 1810 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - de Otano, Pedro Ruiz, Senor Conde de Perez Galvez, 1808 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - de Otano, Pedro Ruiz, Senor Conde de Perez Galvez, 1808 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - de Otano, Pedro Ruiz, Senor Conde de Perez Galvez, 1808 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - de Otano, Pedro Ruiz, Senor Conde de Perez Galvez, 1808 November 2 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Eugenio Juarregi Sologurem, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 October 8 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 October 8 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Martin del Gollado, 1808 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Manuel [illegible] Fuentes, 1808 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Martin de la Riva, 1808 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Garcia Rebollo, 1808 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan de Galvez, 1808 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Maria Flores, 1808 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Eugenio Juarregui Sologurem, 1808 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Jose Aguilera, 1808 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Ignacio de Aguilera, 1808 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Pelaez [illegible], 1808 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Juan Jose Garcia, 1808 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Francisco Moreno, 1808 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - de Perez Galvez, Senor Conde, Francisco Moreno, 1808 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - De Aboro, Alcalde (Superior Gubierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerta Rico), 1859 February 8 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico, Hatillo), 1859 February 12 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegada De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1859 February 12 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegada De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1859 February 12 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento, Camuy, Quebradillas (Superior Gobierno Capatania General y Superintendencia Delegada De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1859 February 12 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento (Superior Gobierno Capatania General y Superintendencia Delegada De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1860 February 23 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento, Arecibo (Sr. Govierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegada De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1860 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento (Superior Govierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico) Alcalde of Utuado, 1860 March 7 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento, Ciales (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1860 December 4 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento, Hatillo, (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1860 December 4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento, Utuado (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1860 January 22 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - De Arecivo, Alcalde, Lopez oBanos, Capitania General y Goberino Superior Politico, 1860 January 22 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento, Utuado (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1860 December 19 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified, Sr. Comandante del Segundo Departamento, Ciales (Superior Gobierno Capitania General y Superintendencia Delegado De Real Hacienda de Puerto Rico), 1860 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 14)